[Music]
hello everybody great to be with you
have a good evening have a good day uh
so let's see who all is with us uh so as
you know today is the 41st live episode
of oscar widget today we discuss indian
history
and let's see who all we have with us we
have vinit jignesh
rajkumar gupta
vishwa karma prakhar
neha aditya abhilash parth
rishabh
and many other people navaneet
partha
good evening good day everybody it's
great to be back with you
so today we discuss indian history i
have chosen a large number of questions
that you have asked in the comments
and let us begin with question number
one
so question number one is by harbinger
can you shed some light on the abbasid
caliphate in invasion of india
and their defeat
so let us understand what these
caliphates are what are these caliphates
so there were four major caliphates
so caliphate is an islamic system of
governance the head of state is called
the caliph
and it essentially is
ruled by sharia law
so there were four major caliphates in
the islamic world the first one was the
rashidun caliphate
which
started i think in 632
a.d
right after the death of the prophet of
islam
and it lasted until 661 a.d and the
capital of this caliphate was in madina
and kufa so this is the rashidun
caliphate the second major caliphate is
the
umayyad caliphate which was from 661 to
750 a.d its capital was damascus the
third caliphate was the abbasid
caliphate the one you have mentioned
its capital was baghdad mostly
and it it its period was from 750 a.d to
1258 a.d
it ended with the destruction of baghdad
by the mongol empire
under hulagu khan
and the fourth and last major caliphate
was the ottoman caliphate which was
based in constantinople it was the
ottoman empire
and the caliphate so the
ottoman emperor was the caliph so the
question you asked is about the abbasid
caliphate the third caliphate between
750 a.d and 1258
ad so
if you look at the first
islamic invasion of india the very first
attempt to invade india
it was during the umayyad caliphate when
this guy called mohammed bin qasim
trying to try to invade sindh the
western part of india and he was
successful to a small extent he was able
to defeat i think raja dahir was it
and he so there was the first person who
actually was able to capture a small
piece of indian territory
so that was parts of balochistan and the
western part of sindh
now the
abbasid caliphate that time duration saw
a great number of uh turkic invasions
into india
so these were islamic invasions for sure
but these were not from the abbasid
caliphate itself these invasions came in
from the north west of india from the
turkic
occupied territories of central asia
so there were many such invasions many
of waves of invasions you had invasions
by the afghans who had been con
converted to islam
so you were so uh afghanistan was also
being ruled by turkic dynasties first
you had the gories and then you the
ghaznavis etc right and then you had the
invasion by the mamluk dynasty
these slave sultans who who invaded
india and who were able to capture small
parts of northern india and gradually
wave by wave they were able to
extend their
their rule further into other parts of
india
so this is all about the uh turkic
invasions which happened
between
uh the 10th 9th 10th centuries until
until the 13th century approximately so
this is the time duration of the abbasid
caliphate and that's when you had all
these
multiple waves of turkic invasions and
there was fierce resistance to these
invasions from
mostly the people from northern and
western india the rajputs essentially
there was fierce resistance for
centuries there were so many ways of
invasions and the indians were able to
repel them repeatedly decade after
decade century of a century until
eventually
uh these guys were ma were able to make
some major breakthroughs
so that in brief is about the
invasions of india during the
uh time period of the abbasid caliphate
so these were not invasions from the
caliphate itself these were turkic
invasions from the northwest of india
mainly through the khyber pass
so that's about this question
let's move on to the next one
so sanjay says
shakkas or skeethians are not indian
then why is the skitian shakka calendar
our national calendar and not the vikram
samwat
calendar
okay so let's understand who the
skittions were
so those keithians were the the people
they were nomadic peoples
in today's
academic environment they are classified
as iranian peoples okay
and these are peoples who uh these were
nomads nomadic clans and tribes who
peopled the entirety of the central
asian eurasian plateau the entire steppe
region of of eurasia from eastern europe
all the way into the xinjiang the
presentation region of china
so these were various uh
they call them iranic peoples which i
completely disagree with okay
now
who are these people you say they were
not indian
so they certainly invaded india from
outside of of the geography of india but
who are these people what was their
culture what was their ancestry
so as we know and as we have discussed
before on this channel there were many
waves of migrations out of india many
thousands of years before today these
are attested in ancient vedic texts etc
during the mahabharata even before the
mahabharata during the rig vedic era etc
there was this battle of ten kings and
many clans were expelled out of india
they had to go into exile they never
came back
so these peoples these clans vedic clans
post vedic clans etc various kings
kingdoms they went out of india they
went essentially north west of india and
north of india so the region north of
india
came to be known as uttar kuru which is
the present-day tarim basin region of
present-day china
uh the so-called xinjiang region so that
was known as uttar kuru
and there was another region called
uttara madra which is the region near
the caspian sea so the whole of central
asia essentially
so this was peopled by indians
by indian clans and tribes that that
migrated out of india some went into
exile after losing battles or wars some
just moved out for for greener pastures
or whatever the reason was so there were
many waves of migrations out of india
these were
originally vedic and post vedic plants
later on their rituals changed they
stopped following the vedic
traditions
properly and therefore they came to be
considered and categorized as lectures
because they were no longer the rituals
were no longer pure but these were
the descendants of indian people and it
is their descendants
who came to be known as the shakka
people the skittion people
and
there has been plenty of dna analysis of
various kitten mummies etc and
we know what they look like in in
popular
in popular art they are they are shown
as having blue eyes and blonde hair and
red hair
and white skin
but if you look at their if you actually
examine their dna and multiple tests
have been done it's very clear what they
look like they had light brown skin they
had dark hair and they had brown eyes so
that's what these kittens looked like so
they were the descendants of ancient
indians and they invaded india so it was
a circular migration
ancient indians went out of india
populated the the
eurasian
steppe region and many thousand years
many thousands of years later they
re-invaded india they re-migrated back
into india
so they were you could say they were not
indians because they came
from beyond india's geographical domain
but they were the descendants of indians
and it is well known that their culture
and all of that was quite similar to
that of india and it is well known that
there was no friction between the
uh sketchians who came into india and
assimilated into the indian population
there was no friction between them and
the indian people so it's clear that
their language was very similar the
culture was also very similar they were
sun worshippers essentially
they worshipped the sun
so these are the scythians the shakkas
now uh there are two like you said there
are two calendars in actually there were
multiple calendars in ancient india
there is a calendar that is uh based on
the
on the date of nirvana of mahavira
which is in the sixth century i think
bce
right so there's a calendar based on
that there was an older calendar called
the saptarshi calendar which was in the
sixth from the sixth millennium bce
six thousand something bce so that's
when it started can you imagine how
ancient our civilization is that we were
we were reckoning time from 6000 bce or
thereabouts
and then we have these two calendars the
shakka calendar and the vikram summer
calendar so i think the vikram somewhat
calendar is uh
when was it
it was somewhere the vikram era begins i
think in 57 bce
so the story is that the great emperor
vikramaditya of ujjain
was able to
defeat invading sketians invading shakka
people he was able to defeat them and
repress their invasion
and
this was commemorated by the starting of
this new vikram somewhat era in i think
57 bce so that is the vikram somewhat
calendar the vikram samath era
and then you have the shakka era which
is
a.d
it's more than a century it starts more
than a century after the vikram samad
era and it
essentially commemorate it marks the
coming to power of this kitchen king
chashtana
who was a was a king of the western
chatrapas
his his domain was i think also ujjain
if i'm not mistaken
but his kingdom he had a large kingdom
it was in western india the western
dynasty was he was one of the major
kings of this uh
of this particular dynasty
so his coming to power happened i think
in 78 80 and that is the beginning of
the shakka era this kythen calendar and
this was what was adopted in india after
this time
this shaka calendar was is also adopted
it was also used to a great extent in
southeast asia
in indonesia bali and various other
parts the champa kingdom the funan
kingdom
and maybe even in the philippines so it
was a very widespread calendar
now why was this calendar taken as the
national character instead of the vikram
somewhat i don't really know maybe
there's some political reason or what it
was maybe
you know how the nih regime was right
uh they like to glorify invaders and
they may be considered these kithyas as
invaders even though they were like
not really very different from indians
they did not impose a foreign culture on
india they assimilated harmoniously into
indian culture but whatever is the
reason they this this kitchen calendar
the shakka calendar was adopted as
india's national calendar even though
many indians many hindus still reckon
time based on the vikram samhat era
so i think in india's official
communications in the ministry of
foreign affairs and various ministries
there are two dates given in each
communique one is this the christian
date and one is the shakka date based on
the shakka calendar maybe we should
introduce the third one the vikram samut
calendar as well
uh
so it it makes sense to have a national
calendar that is based in our own based
in our own
traditions
so that's what it is that's that's the
shakka calendar
so that that's the answer in in brief
next question
jk says there are two questions what is
the first question is what's the origin
and history of the patel caste of
gujarat i've read some words they came
down from the palmyr
valley in today's tajikistan is it true
and the second question is there's a
theory by someone called whatever that
the asiatic lands in gujarat were
brought into india
recently by the mughals from persia
for hunting purposes but we know that
the ashoka pillar the thumb
is
two and a half thousand years old it's a
very very famous symbol of india
so is there any evidence that lions were
present in india during the harappan era
okay as regards the first question i
don't really know or what is the origin
of the patel caste is it a cast i'm not
sure it's a cast because the word caste
is a foreign origin we don't have castes
in india
of course today we are classified into
into forecasts because of the colonial
government but we had the varnajati
system which is a much more complex
system the patients i think are an
agricultural people they're not only
uh
found in gujarat you have patel's in
maharashtra also i think even in
karnataka even in madhya pradesh etc so
i think these are
this is a farming community community
agricultural community quite prosperous
today you find them all over the world
especially in the united states north
america etc you see patel's everywhere
every motel is owned by a patel
but i don't really know what is the
origin did do they come from the promise
i i don't really know i don't think they
are from the palmers
it's not one ethnicity it's it's a
it's kind of a title it's kind of a
occupation that you're a patel means
you're a farmer if i am not mistaken
that's what i know i am not an expert in
this topic so that's all i have to say
about that question two is about lions
did the mughals bring lions into india
have we we've been blessed by the
mughals in this in the form of them
introducing lions into india well that's
completely nonsense
i i don't know where this myth has come
from
lions have been
uh
found in india for thousands of years
so let me
share the screen
there you are this is
a clay
jar of sorts from the harappan era it's
probably five five and a half thousand
years old
it clearly depicts a lion
so it is clear that the harappan or the
the harappan era
of our civilization
we had lions in india at the time yeah i
think we have found fossilized remains
of lions that go much beyond before that
time itself
and it's well known that alliance were
found throughout india not only in
gujarat it's only recently that they've
gone extinct from
from all over asia so in the past lions
were found all the way up to bengal
present-day bangladesh president of west
bengal and madhya pradesh and other
parts of india i think even some parts
of southern india as well they were
found in sindh in in punjab
western india
balochistan and they were also found in
persia in iran
and even in parts of turkey and in and
also in arabia
but
because of colonization mostly these
lions were hunted down and today they
are only found in the gear forest region
of south of saurashtra in gujarat
so like i showed you the
the
lions were very well known during the
harappan times
so the harappan times were the so in
india india was the only
uh geographical region only civilization
that knew not only the lion but also the
tiger so this is the depiction of a
tiger from a harappan ira
clay tablet you can see there's a person
on a platform kind of thing on a tree
and there's a tiger looking at that
individual
so this is a depiction of a tiger from
the harappan area era and here we have a
depiction of a lion isn't that
interesting
so uh
to answer again in brief to conclude
lions have been known in india for
thousands of years they have always been
part of this landscape
okay next question
recently the famous bollywood director
kabir khan said that he feels bad
whenever mughals are portrayed in an
evil manner
in movies because they were nation
builders what do you think of this
statement and do you agree with it
mughal's nation builders they were more
like nation destroyers they were foreign
invaders
foreign occupiers
they did not build india they did not
strengthen india
they did not promote india's national
interest in the sense that
the civilizational interest they did not
promote india's culture on the contrary
they destroyed india's culture they they
went out of their way to systematically
destroy india's culture and try to
impose a foreign culture and religion on
india so i do not see how this is nation
building of any sort
they were certainly trying to construct
a different kind of nation they were
trying to warp distort
india the indian civilization and
convert it into something
foreign
so i do not see that as nation building
i see that as a
an oppressive theoretical activity
and i don't
and if you examine the life and career
of each of the so-called tarkov mughal
kings from whether it starts from babar
humayun akbar and whoever else came
after them up to aurangzeb and the
lesser kings they were all tyrants they
were all oppressors none of them did
anything good for india yeah sure they
built certain monuments and all by
destroying indian architecture sacred
architecture and repurposing
the stones and bricks into into building
something else
and all of that was built with indian
labor and indian money with money
extracted out of india so i don't think
we have anything to thank them for
and they were not nation builders now
when it comes to this individual kabir
khan
i remember the he his first movie was
called kabul express now i don't watch
bollywood movies i have i may have seen
maybe one or two bollywood movies in the
past 10 years recently i tried to watch
this shere shah movie i could not last
more than 10 minutes
it was atrocious this love story and
whatever it was so my point is i don't
watch bollywood movies but in 2010
6 7
sometime around then he came up with
this movie called kabul express i had
seen i had watched that movie at the
time
and if you see that movie there is so
much racism against the
against the hazara people of afghanistan
they are portrayed as donkeys and they
are portrayed as subhumans in this movie
so this is the kind of attitude these
bollywood directors have and then they
come back and lecture us about nation
building and the greatness of these
mughals come on
they are the last people to lecture us
about anything bollywood doesn't depict
indian culture it is not something that
that strengthens india's culture and
india's soft power it is something that
tries to misport india so these are the
last people we need to take advice from
or to learn anything from if you look at
their so-called historical movies they
all distort history
and they only show a certain flavor of
history you know a certain ideological
flavor of history so the best thing we
should do is to boycott bollywood stop
watching bollywood movies
there are plenty other forms of
entertainment that are available today
so
that it is best to just
render these people irrelevant
okay joseph matthew says what is the
religion according to you do you why do
you consider monotheism polytheism and
atheism to be all part of hinduism and
what is the culture of a land
how much is there between religion and
culture
yeah so i have uh spoken about this in
the past i think a couple of times
perhaps
so do i okay what's a religion so
religion is a western concept
in india we have the concept of dharma
which is a
very much wider concept in the western
uh perception of religion a religion is
something that has one prophet one god
and one book and everybody follows that
that is the western concept of religion
and that uh
that has been
force fitted on eastern cultures
so eastern cultures are have always been
polytheistic even the ancient arabic
culture was polytheistic actually
so this
foreign western abrahamic concept of one
book one prophet one god has been
force-fitted
on eastern cultures eastern traditions
and that's how today we all see it
because this is the way we are taught
about religion so then we they have
imposed this ism suffix
onto eastern traditions hinduism
tengrism confucianism taoism
and whatever else shinto ism
so that's the kind of thing that's been
done uh
our
traditions are very
very diverse very wide now why do i
consider monotheism polyhedra mythician
to be part of hinduism
well
it's
so what is hinduism it's essentially a
number of ancient philosophical
traditions
a number of interrelated interconnected
philosophical souls of thoughts thought
that are extremely diverse so i have
spoken about this in the past let me
give you a very brief overview overview
again
so we have i think eight or nine schools
of thought in hinduism major schools of
thought there are many other smaller
schools of thought
the first one is charvaka which is
atheism it is pure materialism it it
rejects the
existence of god then you have the jaina
school of thought of philosophy which
does believe in karma and rebirth but it
is also an atheistic school of thought
it rejects the existence of any god and
you have the both the philosophy which
is again a dharmic philosophy
it believes in karma and rebirth but it
is again
mostly atheistic it rejects the
existence of god then you have nyaya
which is realistic
it is a realistic philosophy based upon
logic so in
the atma or the self is distinct from
the mind and the body there is karma and
rebirth and it does believe in the
existence of god
that is nyaya then you have vaishyasik
in which you there is the belief in
karma and rebirth and there is a belief
in the existence of god then you have
the sankhya philosophy which is the
holistic realism
in which there is no need for god then
you have yoga philosophy which admits
the existence of god and it is
essentially a form of sankya theistic
sankhya then you have memansa which is
based upon the vedas
so in this philosophy the soul is
immortal it is eternal but there is no
supreme god there is no creator god so
this is a
skeptical theory atheistic theory
to some extent it does believe in the
law of karma it says this law is an
autonomous natural and moral
law that rules the world and finally we
have vedanta which says that there
exists a supreme person who permeates
the entire universe and yet who remains
beyond it so these are the major schools
of thought of
what we call hinduism today as you can
see there is such a wide panoply of
ideas and beliefs and
and it's different systems so you have
monotheistic aspects to it like vedanta
says there is a supreme person who
permeates the universe and yet is beyond
it
so you could interpret that as
kind of being monotheistic but there are
so many different aspects of this
divinity which manifest them
themselves in a variety of ways which we
call these different gods right 64 crore
gods or whatever the hell they call it
in hinduism it's not 64 crore gods this
is the western concept it's a western
myth anyhow so you have polytheism you
have monotheism you also have skepticism
in atheism you have materialism and you
have spiritualism and what not so it's a
very diverse
tradition so many different
schools of thought and therefore all of
these schools of thought they encompass
all of these different viewpoints and
philosophies and they are all part of
hinduism however the abrahamic
abrahamic monotheism is in no way part
of dharma it is actually a dharma if you
if you look at it strictly because it it
talks about one god one prophet and one
book and everybody is forced to believe
that you can't go beyond that there is
no
you're not allowed to question anything
you have to blindly obey
blind obedience that is not a dharmic
way of looking at anything
so those
uh belief systems
are clearly not part of hinduism
but the ones i just mentioned the
various ancient indian schools of
thought philosophical thought those
diverse viewpoints are all part of
hinduism
now what's the difference between a
culture and a religion well
in the case of the eastern traditions
there's very little difference between
culture and religion because what what
we call hinduism is not really a
religion because we don't have one book
one god and one
prophet we have so many different
viewpoints so that is all whatever
practices you have in in a society in in
a civilization like india that's all
culture so it manifests itself in the
way you draw the kind of dress you wear
the kind of languages
the kind of festivals you celebrate the
kind of traditions you follow
um the kind of practices you have
rituals you have all of that the kind of
music you play the kind of cuisine you
have all of that
forms what's called culture and clearly
the
what is called religion is a major
component of that
so i hope this explains
in brief
what this is all about
okay eagle eye says did ancient indians
know that the earth was round
that's a good question
so we know
what is the oldest known language in the
world it is sanskrit right
now just we just have to ask this simple
question what is the word for geography
in sanskrit
word for geography in sanskrit is
and what does gold mean
it means spherical
so bhugol shastra bhugol
is essentially the science of the
spherical earth
that's your answer of course we knew in
the past in ancient india that the earth
was round
we never believed in a flat in the flat
earth theory
okay uh the way it says why wasn't there
a huge migration of
the middle eastern population into india
during the muslim rule
india was a much better place to live
than in a desert and there was also no
shortage of hindu slaves and they could
also have outnumbered the local in the
population in a few places etc all that
so the question is was there a huge
migration of the middle eastern
population into india during the
turkey etc occupation of india
so that is a question that lots of
people have asked there's this
and so so let's let's take a look at
look at
a research paper let me quickly share
that with you
let's take a look at it in brief
so
here we are so this is a research paper
from the journal of human genetics
diverse genetic origin of indian muslims
evidence from autosomal str loci
lukai and it's by a number of authors
it's from 2009
so what it says is that
it says that
in the daodhi bharas of tamil nadu and
gujarat and
the iranian shias there is a significant
genetic contribution from west asia
especially iran
so there does seem to be
a little bit
what they call minor gene flow
from western asia
in certain
segments certain minor segments
of the indian muslim
population
but apart from that
the
like it says it says that this study
reveals that the spread of the islamic
faith in the indian indian subcontinent
was predominantly a cultural
transformation associated with minor
gene flow from west asia so that is the
evidence that we have and you can look
up other research papers as well all of
these show similar results so what we
find is that the indian muslims are
mostly like 99
of them
are of indian local origin
whether it is indian muslims or
pakistani muslims or bangladesh muslims
or afghan muslims or sri lankan muslims
or whoever else
within the subcontinent the muslims are
overwhelmingly
of indian ancestry
there are only a few small populations
like the daodi bhoras or whoever it is
who have some
significant contribution from west asia
from for everybody else it's just indian
dna indian origin
so
so the the reason for this is that see
it's very hard for a huge population to
migrate thousands of kilometers it's
what what happened during the turkic and
other invasions of india was that there
was these small
bands of marauders a few thousand
swordsmen horsemen who came with in the
form of armies who conquered
parts of india
and then subjugated the population there
oppressed the population there and
forcibly converted them to their culture
and religion
so that's how it happened this was all
usually male mediated invasions there
were very few females who would come
into the as invaders right so it was
always that sort of a thing
it's always male mediated it's always
military expansion which means
uh
soldiers armies so that's usually a few
ten 000 people 10 20 50 000 maybe 100
000 at maximum
in those days
and that was just a drop of a droplet of
water in the enormous population of the
indian subcontinent and therefore it did
not make any significant genetic impact
in the
indian
uh
genetic landscape
and that's why we find that there is
very little uh genetic component from
west asia
in india's muslims
okay ravi says what's the role of the
roman catholic church in the prosecution
and the genocide of aboriginal cultures
in goa
and the rest of the world
and if hitler is a bad guy for the
genocide of the jews
why is the roman catholic church never
held accountable for the aboriginal
cultural and human genocide it committed
all over the world very good question
so the answer is very simple
history
is written
by the winners
so all your history textbooks all of the
analysis that you find from all these
so-called scholars and historians and
experts and authors and writers it's all
from a euro-centric perspective it's all
from a christian perspective
right and therefore this genocide this
horrifying
genocide that these people perpetrated
with the consent with the uh with the
blessing
of the catholic church etc it's it's all
vital it's all blanked out
it is not mentioned
and our historians also are under the
sway of these people our historians are
essentially coolies
they are sea boys of the west
and therefore they also do not write
about it they do not speak about this
history is always written by the winners
now there is an interesting
question people some people have asked
me
the vikings
the scandinavian vikings of western
europe northwestern europe
they were able to conquer many christian
kingdoms and
sack those kingdoms pillaged them they
destroyed many monasteries they killed
lots of hundreds maybe thousands of
christian monks etc
so how come the history does not portray
them in good light because if you see
the
history the
the way these people have been depicted
in in medieval and later european
historical accounts
they are portrayed as savages and
barbarians it's only now that the
hollywood is making serials about the
vikings historically they have been
portrayed as savages even though they
were able to destroy many christian
kingdoms so
if they won
why are they portrayed in such a manner
and the answer is very simple because
eventually the church won
eventually even the vikings got
converted into christianity the
scandinavian nations are all
christian they have all been christian
until recently
so in the long term
the church won and the vikings lost so
even though they had success at the time
they eventually lost and the people with
the pence were all christian monks
so that's how it goes so the history is
always written by the winners and that's
why you find all this so hitler lost
he lost
and therefore he is portrayed as a
monster even though there have been many
worse monsters i am not saying hitler
was not a monster he was a barbaric
monster he was cruel he was brutal he
killed so many jews and
indian origin romani people and he
deserves to be held in contempt and
portrayed as a monster which he was but
there are many worse monsters what the
what the church did the inquisition and
what not the brutality and genocide of
the of the people of the americas south
america north america the genocide in
india at least 100 million people died
at these people's hands and so much more
and yet no one writes about this it's
because they won and today the entire
narrative is controlled by these people
so that needs to change
next question why do we depict so many
of our gods and characters from etihasa
as light-skinned when they were clearly
mentioned as dark-skinned krishna arjuna
draupadi etc
do you think that if hindu artwork
depicted various skin tones found
throughout india accurately it would
help combat the aryan dravidian
yes so this uh
so there does seem to be this obsession
with fairer skin in india
uh
in in contemporary artwork there is a
certain
bias towards
people who have fairer skin and there is
there are depictions of of
older ancient people also
in in this in this kind of manner
uh our gods the dark-skinned gods are
now depicted as blue whether it is lord
krishna or lord i don't know about if
lord rama was dark skin or not we don't
know about that but he is also depicted
with this blue shade of skin and so is
lord shiva
now the thing is this
it's not always been like that
so let me
give you an example example a picture
speaks a thousand words
so this here is a painting from the
ajanta caves
i think it's in maharashtra isn't it the
arjuna caves now take a look at this
this is clearly a beautiful lovely lady
from our ancient past one of our
ancestors she has dark skin and this is
portrayed as the ideal of beauty right
so there was nothing against dark skin
in ancient india before the various
invasions and occupation of india so
there you go that's one example here's
another one
this again is
a person very graceful
aesthetic looking person with
significantly dark skin
where you have a number of ladies who
all have dark skin some are playing
instruments
one seems to be a royalty person or
whatever so they all have dark skin and
there was nothing against dark sin in
those days
here you see lord buddha himself
depicted as having significantly dark
skin
now we know that the lord buddha was
from northern india
so he
one would imagine that he would have
lighter colored skin and yet in southern
india in maharashtra the ajanta case he
is depicted as having dark skin
so it is very clear from these examples
there are thousands more examples i've
just given you a few so it's very clear
from these examples that there was no
bias
in ancient india
uh about about dark skin
right there was no bias against dark
skin there was no uh
there was no obsession with fair skin in
ancient india all skin colors were
equally
well accepted they were all taken as is
as pleasing and aesthetic so it is this
this
past 1000 years of india's history this
period of foreign occupation subjugation
colonization
that has uh
made that has changed india's person
the perception of the people of india
into regarding people with lighter skin
as superior because earlier it was the
turks who who mostly have lighter skin
than indians
on average and then you have this you
have the europeans who have
lighter skin again than indians so these
guys one
indians lost and therefore we started
looking up on them looking at them as
being superior to us and what what was
the common factor lighter skin
so this is a very recent phenomenon
india's history is 10
maybe 10 000 or more years old this is
something that happened in the past 1000
years in the past
millennium of humiliation so it is all
about
deconditioning ourselves from this
nonsense
it is about decolonizing our minds
getting
rid of this slave mentality that
permeates so many indian minds
all skin colors are equally beautiful
that is what we have to start
understanding again
okay part says what are your views about
beef eating is it right to ban
slaughtering of cows in india
let's see from a different perspective
there are many states in the united
states
where
the slaughter of horses is banned it is
banned by law you cannot slaughter
horses
because in many countries especially
europe etc they people actually eat
horse meat
in the u.s the slaughter of horses
in most states is banned
so why is this no why why does doesn't
this
offend some people why doesn't it go
against freedom of choice
why why don't people protest against
this but this is the u.s right they are
superior to us so we should not question
them there are many i mean not many
every single islamic country
bans
pork
now does anybody protest that no
it is their country it is their religion
their culture and they have the right to
do whatever they whatever their religion
prescribes whatever their culture
prescribes they have the right to do it
and they are justified in my opinion to
ban
the consumption the sale or whatever of
pork
and similarly the americans are fully
justified
in banning the slaughter of horses so
why is india singled art for this
in indian culture whether it is hinduism
jainism buddhism sikhism i'm not sure
about buddhism but yeah
in every dharmic religion in every
dharmic
perspective
the slaughter of cows is the worst thing
you can imagine
cows have been worshipped they have been
held as sacred
even the sikh gurus
banned cow slaughter
so according to india's
ancient cultural practices in in our
ancient civilization
it is not right to kill cows it is not
right to eat beef and therefore it is
completely and perfectly justified to
ban cow slaughter in india now i
understand in certain places in the
northeast where they have never
practiced hinduism in the form it is
practiced in other parts of india i
understand why they would be against the
ban on cows on beef so maybe india can
make an exception for the for certain
parts of the northeast i'm not talking
about manipur manipur is again hindu but
maybe nagaland for example or maybe some
other regions
where one could imagine that we could
make an exception but for the rest of
india
the country is perfectly justified in
banning the slaughter of cows and the
consumption of beef now there is this
other hypocrisy also
certain hindus for whatever reason eat
beef today
and other hindus go after them they
demonize them
right
but the same hindus who demonize other
hindus for eating beef they will worship
rahman
they will worship salman khan
they will worship elon musk they will
worship
benjamin netanyahu all these people eat
beef and they have no these hindus have
no problem
worshiping these beef eaters but they
have a problem if some hindus eat beef
i am not saying eating beef is a good
thing
i don't eat beef
i am saying we should have a ban on
cow's water but as of today if some
hindus eat beef i think
and many of them are actually
in favor of hinduism they are actually
hindus but they have this weakness that
they can't resist the temptation of
eating beef so the world is a is complex
in the 21st century
i think we should go a little easy on
some of us
hindus
who still have this weakness for
whatever reason of eating beef
but i agree with you i mean my view is
that the ban on beef the ban on cow
slaughter is perfectly justifiable it's
perfectly valid every country has the
right to practice its culture
right and our indigenous
culture our 10 000 plus year old culture
says that eating beef is wrong
and again cow's daughter is is is the
worst thing you can do and therefore we
must put that into law and into practice
okay next question since sanskrit and
tamil are separate languages did they
develop separately in different parts of
ancient india
if so why did the chola kings use
sanskrit later on the problem now is is
that we don't really know about the
origins of these of of india's languages
there's very little research been that's
been done there are
hardly any
high quality linguists in india at all
though whatever few linguists we have
are the of the caliber of iran mahadeva
out of a hat
and then you know so we don't have any
research any real proper research being
done on linguistics in india our
historians have no idea
when our language is developed how they
developed in what form they developed
what came before vedic sanskrit there
must have been an older form of sanskrit
proto-sanskrit
and and linguists talk about this
proto-indo-european language which is
something they have imagined out of
their dreams there is no evidence any
such language actually existed i think
if there was a proto-indo-european
language it must have been
proto-sanskrit pre-vedic sanskrit so we
don't know and what about tamil when did
tamil
evolve when did it originate we don't
have the faintest clue and therefore we
have this
this contest that goes on between north
and within the people of tamil nadu and
other people about which language is
older
the oldest known language in the world
is vedic sanskrit by the way and there
is no evidence tamil is anyway anywhere
close to it there it it is a possibility
that tamil may be
similar in age
as
vedic senses but we don't have any
evidence of that
it is actually even possible that
languages like telugu may be older than
sanskrit than tamil
okay so tamil is not the the language
that represents the whole of south india
but we know that it's an ancient
language it's one of india's classical
languages
we don't know
because there is no research about
this so we don't know when this language
is developed how old they are
it is clear that there were many that
india the indian subcontinent was a very
complex environment
there are clearly multiple languages
language families that came out of this
region
we know from genetic data that the
indian subcontinent is the original
founder zone of the out of africa
migration it is from india from the
indian subcontinent that the entire rest
of the world was populated
so india is clearly the birthplace of
all these ancient languages
but we don't know when the seed of
sanskrit was formed when the seed of
tamil emerged we don't know these things
so so i can't answer nobody can answer
as of today right now why did the chola
kings use sanskrit so like i have said
many times
sanskrit is india's civilizational
language today's dravidian parties
have
brainwashed the people of southern india
especially tamil nadu into believing
that there is a aryan darwinian divide
and
the ancient tamil culture was a secular
culture a non-hindu culture all that
nonsense
absolute nonsense absolute garbage
absolute rubbish
the cholas were tamil speaking people
the chola dynasty
is one of the longest reigning dynasties
in known history it was in power
for 1500 years 1500 years
incredible isn't it
and they
even though they were tamil speakers
when they conquered the entirety of
southeast asia they propagated hinduism
and sanskrit throughout these regions
they did not propagate tamil
we do have tamil in malaysia today we do
have we do have tamil spoken in
singapore today it is because of later
tamil migrations during the british
colonial era
it is not because of the cholas
look at the names of people in indonesia
they have sanskrit names not tamil names
look at the names of ancient cities and
kingdoms
in
southeast asia the champa kingdom other
kingdoms look at the names of their
kings they are all indian hindu names
sanskrit names right
so
throughout the indian subcontinent in
ancient days
they have we had the two language system
everybody would learn their mother
tongue
and everybody would learn the
civilizational language sanskrit
and sanskrit always took precedence as
the high language as the prestige
language as the civilizational language
as the language that bound the entire
civilization together from
balochistan and sindh
all the way to the philippines it was
one civilization it was one culture that
that was practiced throughout this
region
and the glue that bound everything
together what was what we call hinduism
today and it was the sanskrit language
and that's why the cholas used sanskrit
and that's why they propagated sanskrit
everywhere they conquered
okay next question
this is by sahir al-haq
why do some indo-european languages have
grammatical genders
but some don't
how does a language become gender
neutral and why does hindi have this
weird grammar of assigning gender to
inanimate objects
by the way i am a native bengali speaker
so you are right there is this thing
about uh gender in in uh
so
the oldest known language in human
history is vedic sanskrit now vedic
sanskrit is a very complex language
it has this gender structure there are
three genders
in
ancient vedic sanskrit and classical
sanskrit of panini as well you have the
masculine gender the feminine gender and
you have a neutral gender as well
so for instance take
take the word for bird which is pakshi
pakshi is the word for bird in sanskrit
it's a neutral it's it it is a it's a
gender-neutral word
it has the neutral gender
but now you have certain species of
pakshi let's say kokila
kokilah or or sarika so these are two
different species of bird
both of these birds have masculine and
feminine genders within them but the
names of these species of birds sarika
and kokila
are
feminine names right
now take the name
of or what is the word for horse in
sanskrit it's ashwa
now ashwa is a masculine
word even though horses have male and
female genders both but the noun ashwa
is a masculine noun
take an in an inanimate object let's say
the common kitchen knife churika
in sanskrit that's a feminine noun even
though it's an inanimate object
so
most likely it is proto-sanskrit which
was the mother of all the indo-european
languages right and you find this sort
of
gender
uh
grammatical genders in various
indo-european languages now you know in
in
in the western uh world view
the people of ancient older times were
very simple and the people who came
later were more evolved and the 21st
century we are the most evolved people
that we that the planet earth has ever
seen
now if we look at
the sanskrit language it is a highly
complex language and the history of the
evolution of indo-european languages is
the history of the loss of complexity
so the descendant languages of vedic
sanskrit
became progressively simpler and less
complex
right
so for example the word for i was chaku
it became akshay it became
the word for
hand was hasta which became heart
the word for fish was matsia which
became much
so as you can see there is a
loss of complexity as the languages
became up
became apprentice
they underwent the process of up branch
which means corruption
and the same happened for languages like
persian
like armenian for the various other
indo-european languages which are spoken
in europe there is a gradual
lack loss of complexity
and so in some languages the loss of
complexity manifested itself in the form
of loss of certain genders so there are
certain languages in which you only have
two genders
there are certain languages in which you
have no gender at all
to which is assigned to nouns
for instance in in
in french you have genders
every word has a gender the word for
chair is chez
lashes it's not lucious
and so on la lutable and so on so forth
so so words even inanimate objects have
genders in french in german and other
languages but in some languages the
gender is not there so it is because of
the
different ways in which languages lost
complexity the older and euro
indo-european language is the more
complex it is
so that's how it happened in brief
uh the process is not very well
understood by linguists linguistics is
not an exact science it is not even a
science it is uh
a great deal of linguistics is actually
all
voodoo
and it's all made up
so unfortunately there is no linguistic
no genuine linguistics research that is
being done in india
so i hope that changes but yeah that's
how the process happened
sujoy
says that i have recently found about
the violence of killing infidels and
godless people in hymns of vedas
being not able to read sanskrit i don't
know how much this is true and how much
is interpretation or misinterpretation
can you share your views
so first of all okay good question so
this is a a problem that many many many
people have
see there is no concept of infidels
in the dharmic practices in the dharmic
world view there are no infidels like i
said some time ago like i demonstrated
some time ago
atheism is very much part
is very much of one of the schools of
thought or a couple of schools of
thought of the dharmic
culture
so so if if somebody is atheist which
means godless charvaka for example the
charwakas were not killed for not
believing in god
i mean it was their it was their their
problem so to say
it's your problem if you don't believe
in god nobody bothered anyone for having
a certain belief
and again there are no infidels or
kafirs in hinduism or or any
any dharmic
religion so to say right so i don't know
where you have found about violence of
killing infidels and godless people in
the hymns of the vedas come on there's
no thing
uh maybe you have read some translation
maybe you have read some
misinterpretation of the of the vedas
so the the solution to this is to learn
sanskrit
and indians
think about sanskrit as being extremely
complex like quantum mechanics or
something it's not
sanskrit is a language that is part of
the vocabulary of every indian language
of of more than 90 percent of indian
languages today
whether you speak hindi or marathi or
gujarati or assamese or
or or bishnupriya manipuri
or sinhalese or tamil or telugu or
kannada
or
or malayalam
even if you speak pashto or kashmiri you
will find elements of sanskrit in there
even if you speak persian you will find
sanskrit elements in there sanskrit is
still a living breathing language it's
not hard to learn sanskrit it's actually
quite easy
so one of the so the best book i have
found for learning sanskrit is called
sanskrit swam shikshak maybe i'll put a
link in the description below maybe i
will do a giveaway of that book next
month i'm gonna do a monthly book
giveaway maybe i will give away a few
copies of that book in the next giveaway
so sanskrit is our
civilizational language it is our
ancestral language it is very easy to
learn you can learn it in a few weeks
you can
you can acquire a good working
understanding of in just a few weeks
so it's something that everybody should
invest in it is an investment in your
own
in improving yourself and understanding
your own culture and heritage
chi ching says are the people from the
northeast region of india from the
mongolian race a good question and this
is a question people have asked me many
times i think i've answered it at least
once but let me i'm happy to answer it
again
so
uh are the people of northeast india
mongolians or descendants of mongolians
or from the mongolian race is the
question so the concept of race is
a 19th century colonial concept there is
no such thing as a race
it is an unscientific term there is no
there is no scientific definition of
race there is no scientific definition
of the boundaries between race and when
one race ends and another race begins
there is actually not even a proper
scientific definition of the boundaries
between species
right there is no such thing as a pure
race there is not something as a pure
ethnicity there is no such thing as a
pure species either right
so uh so what are the people of the
northeast what is their heritage what is
their ancestry so one of the ways of
looking at this in in a good ways is to
look at the linguistics
of northeastern india so you have a
number of languages in northeastern
india
you have a a variety of naga languages
for example you have mao rayma tankul
marin koya koinak etc you have the
cookie chin languages in northeastern
india you have the methi language
of manipur you have the karbi language
etc so all of these languages if you
look at them if you examine them the
naga languages are classified under the
sino-tibetan language family so it is
not a mongolic or language
family it's classified under the cyano
tibetan language family
and it's more tibetan than sino actually
there's very little sinic component even
in the tibetan language
so essentially it is a it is
the naga languages of various naga
languages
many of which are not mutually
intelligible they are
all part of the
so-called sino-tibetan language family
the cookie chin language again is part
of the the cookie chain languages
are part of the sino-tibetan language
family the meet language methi language
is part of the tibeto-burman language
family
it's closer to burmese and to some
extent to the tibetan language the karbi
language again is part of the
sino-tibetan language family
if we know the history of the northeast
is very complex the people of assam the
hom people were actually
uh originally of the thai ethnicity so
they spoke of thai language today's
assassin's language is a mixture of thai
words or thai
language
and it has some sanskrit substratum to
it
and all that so it's it's kind of a
mixed bag the assam is language today
and similarly you have the other
languages which are spoken in
meghalaya for example which would be
part of various such
local
language families
and so on
so the
the uh
the people of this region they have come
as a result they have they
have come to inhabit
this region called northeast india as a
result of migrations local regional
migrations from either yunnan or from
the
thai thai country like thai regions from
thailand or or burma et cetera
the the cookies are essentially from
east of india in burma but now they are
also inhabiting parts of northeast india
and so on so it's a mixed bag it's a
complex history it's a complex
bag of linguistics but there is clearly
no mongolian
component in this
so that is the answer in brief
there is no real mongolian component in
in the in either the linguistics or the
genetics
or the ethnic heritage of the people of
northeast india
okay next question
suyash says
i believe in what you said about
netaji's leadership subhash and rabosa's
leadership and his iron fist rule my
question is
one of nithaji's most trusted army
commanders was habibu rahman
who accompanied him on his supposed last
flight
so rahman later joined the attacking
pakistani forces in the 1948 war of
kashmir was netaji trusting the wrong
persons or the wrong ideology
this is a very good question
so you are right one of his closest uh
and most trusted
lieutenants habibu rahman who was part
of the indian national army who who
fought for india's independence on the
british he later joined pakistan he
became a pakistani and he was part of
this uh
invasion of kashmir and occupation of
kashmir so
did subhash chandra bose trust the wrong
person that's the question very good
question very good question
here's what it is
he did not trust the wrong people he
trusted the right people people like
khabib rahman and many other indian
muslims who may have later become
pakistanis they all
fought under the leadership of sebastian
rabos they lived together with hindus
and sikhs and other people they lived
together they fought together for
india's independence they bled together
they died together many of them for
india's independence
because of the leadership of this great
man subhash chandra bose it is
subhashin-rabo's
subscribe the india they sought to
construct was a distorted twisted
reduced
version of what india actually could
have been and that leadership was not
palatable to people
who fought under subhash and rebels
and therefore people like rahman then
went elsewhere
they sought some other leadership maybe
they found that pakistan is better for
me now now that's washington rebels is
no longer there
they clearly believed that they clearly
knew that had subhash chandra bose won
then india would have been a great
country and they wanted to be part of
that great india but they did not want
to be part of nehru and gandhi's india
which was a mediocre version of india
and that's why they went to pakistan and
it's very
so that's so that's the reason they
believe that pakistan could be a better
country than nehru and gandhi's india
so it's all about leadership it's all
about vision
under substitute india would have been a
completely different country
and that's the country they would have
loved to live in that's the country they
were willing to die for
it's all about leadership
if you look at india and pakistan if you
compare india and pakistan's foreign
policy etc you will find
to your great surprise in shock
that pakistan
implements and follows
chanakya niti far better than india
that is the sad truth
so yes people preferred to go to
pakistan than to live in gandhi and
narrows
india
so it doesn't mean that subhash and
rabos trusted the wrong people
it means that under his leadership they
trusted and believed in him and they
knew that had he won india would have
been great so that's why they fought for
him but after he disappeared whatever
happened to him they preferred to join
pakistan because they they knew
that pakistan
for them would be better than nehru and
gandhi's india
siddhant says why did gandhi love nehru
so much that he favored fought for and
defended nehru over every other
prominent leader in the congress party
well what do i say my friends except
saying the truth
that gandhi was a british agent
and the british wanted nehru
to take over the leadership position of
india after they handed over power after
the transferred power
and there were clearly better candidates
than nehru in the congress party and
therefore mr british agent
mr mohandas
he ensured
that the will of the british was
implemented and everybody else was
sidelined
that is the short brief and
real truthful answer that mr gandhi mr
mundus gandhi was nothing more than a
british agent
he did not love anybody he did not even
love his own wife if you look if you
examine his biography and his history
but
he he loved the british
he was a loyal servant of the british
and that's why
he favored nehru supported nehru fought
for nehru and cleared the path for nehru
to ascend to
the possession of prime minister of
india that's it
rahma krishna says that i completely
agree with you that reservation dilutes
the competition for people entering the
taiwan colleges and reduces the overall
quality of students but i am someone who
benefited from the same
and had the incredible fortune
of studying in an indian institute of
technology
what will you advise many other students
like me who might feel undeserving or
discouraged for for using reservation as
i know personally many quota students
also face discrimination from other
general category students
for using reservations
this is the sad state of affairs in
india because of reservations
that good people intelligent people
bright people
feel undeserving and they feel
discouraged because they were able to
benefit from this policy of reservations
look
there is no need for you to feel
undeserving
do not feel discouraged
it is just the way it is the
structure of the governance system the
environment in india is the way it is
and you we we all have to live within
that
students who
are able to benefit from the policy of
reservation
should obviously benefit from it i mean
should they reject it no if if good
fortune smiles upon you you should
embrace it
the fact is that all indians are
brilliant all indians are intelligent
whether they are from a certain category
from a reserved category or general
category it doesn't matter all indians
are
indians are the most intelligent people
in the world we and history proves this
so if you benefited from reservation
well that just that's nothing more than
good fortune it doesn't mean that you
are undeserving it doesn't mean you
should feel discouraged it doesn't mean
you should feel ashamed
just make the best of your life and
that's all it doesn't matter from what
kind of path you took
through your education system what
really matters
is what you do with the rest of your
life
and if you're able to do something good
if you're able to achieve something
significant
then you are clearly somebody who is
very much deserving of every accolade
that comes their way
so i would say that those students who
benefit from reservations should benefit
from them and they should not feel
ashamed of it they should not feel
undeserving and
the general category people
should
should not dis discriminate against them
or or
or any any thing it's it's not anybody's
fault it is the fault of the government
of india
i'm not talking about the present
government i'm talking about the entire
series of governments we have here in
india who which have implemented these
policies i think it began in the 1990s
this reservation system
they have done this for their personal
benefits for getting votes for creating
vote banks and all that it is they who
are to blame for this it is not the
students or the people of india who are
to blame for this and therefore there is
it is completely wrong to feel ashamed
of it or feel that you are undeserving
or to feel discouraged it's just the way
this country is right now we will
eventually move past this we will get
better leadership we will get
better governance in the country in the
future as of now it's just the way it is
okay today we saw ashraf ghani abandon
his people
has an indian king or leader
ever excuse me has an indian king or
leader ever abandoned his people
the mere thought of something like this
happening to india and her people scares
me
so it's clear that this comment was from
a few days ago when mr ashraf ghani fled
from afghanistan as the taliban was
taking over
the question is has an indian king or
leader ever abandoned his people
i don't know of any indian king who has
fled from the battlefield indian kings
have always
been happy to die fighting for their
principles and for their people
but
has any indian leader abandoned his
people
sadly
sadly yes
the chinese advanced past arunachal
pradesh
and assam was at their mercy
and our
magnificent prime minister sri jawala
nehru said on all india radio
that my heart goes out for the people of
assam
he said that his heart goes out for the
people of assam he did not order the
army
to fight the chinese he did not allow
the air force to enter the battlefield
but he said that his heart went out to
the people of assam
he had given up on assam
mr nehru had abandoned the people of
assam which was then almost the entirety
of northeast india that is
an example of an indian leader
an elected leader a prime minister
abandoning his people remember the name
shri jawaharlal nehru
and i am not making this up google it
it's well known that this happened
dave sharma says why did great ancient
indian kingdoms fall
we had such great rulers and people like
chanakya then why couldn't they choose a
worthy successor for the kingdom
and why did kingdoms like marathas and
rajputs fight against each other rather
than their collective goal which should
have been removing turks off the
subcontinent
see vishnu gupta chanakya chose
a brilliant person as the emperor of
india which was chandragupta maurya
chandragupta's more chandragupta
maurya's successor was also good his son
bindusar
bindusar's son was this great tyrant
called
ashok who nevertheless was able to rule
india and consolidated the rule over the
whole of the country
including
all the way west
north et cetera in afghanistan etc so
these
so ashok may not have been a good person
but he was a very strong ruler
now why do kingdoms dynasties empires
fall it's always
because
the succession plan goes wrong
either
the new leader who comes after the
demise or the abdication or whatever
passing on of the previous leader
the new leader who comes is either weak
or is
undeserving so eventually after a number
of great kings or emperors you always
have somebody who is weak
and that's where everything goes wrong
in some cases you have a dynasty that
lasts for more than a thousand years
like the cholas almost 1500 years so
they clearly had a good mechanism of
succession
that they were able to last that long
but in the case of the marathas you know
that after a few few iterations of of
peshwas you had too much infighting and
they squandered it away sadly
and the british were able to take over
in the case
of the kushans you had somebody as great
as the as kanishka the great who
influenced the whole of asia essentially
and even is in the case of the of the
questions after kanishka you had lesser
and lesser kings and eventually the
kushan empire the quran dynasty
disappeared
the same happened with the guptas
the same happened with vijayanagar
empire in which case
they trusted the wrong people the gilani
brothers and gave them significant
prominent positions in the army and they
were backstabbed right
aliya devaraya the last vijanagar great
king
and so on
and it's also a question of leadership
the marathas and the rajputs they fought
each other instead of uniting because
there was no great leader who could
unify these two
competing forces
a country like india i've said many
times needs
a towering personality a once in a
thousand years kind of person to unify
the subcontinent so it is that it is
these factors that have caused the
the demise of ancient indian kingdoms
from time to time
get great golden ages like the gupta era
etc and again it it ended
then you had this period of
fragmentation and because india was
fragmented the foreigners were able to
invade and occupy and eventually
oppress and subjugate the country
yet india says that we know that india
had vedic sanskrit as the language
according to findings it is more than 12
000 years old
then why does the indus valley
civilization language remain a question
isn't it vedic sanskrit and if it is not
isn't that a contradiction to the claim
of our invasion theory that the vedas
were written around 2500 bc because if
they were then
then the indus valley civilization
scripts would they have been in vedic
sanctuary as well
listen a script is not a language a
language is not a script
you can write tamil in the karoshi
script you can write tamil in the brahmi
script you can also write sanskrit in
the brahmi script a script is merely a
vehicle
it is not a language
right
now we don't know what the so called
harappan script is we have not been able
to decipher it so we don't know what
language it is
as far as you saying that
according to finding sanskrit is more
than 12 000 years old no
where does it where have we found this
what evidence do we have that sanskrit
is more than 12 000 years old i am not
saying it is not
it could very well be more than 12 000
years old
but we have no evidence of that we need
incontrovertible evidence
to be able to make this claim and no
such evidence exists as of today
the oldest
evidence of sanskrit
is from present-day syria
the methane kingdom
the great horse master ke kuli
who used sanskrit terminology
in his horse training manual
so this mathani kingdom was essentially
an out of india migration that happened
about 3500 years ago
and that is the oldest evidence of
written sanskrit that we have today
if it is found that the harappan
script is indeed
depicting the sanskrit language
then we will know that sanskrit is more
than five six thousand years old as of
today we don't have the evidence of that
right
the rn invasion theory claims that the
vedas written were written after
1500 bce this theory says that there was
an invasion or migration
about
1500 bce or thereabouts
these foreign white skinned aryans came
into india
and they settled down in the subtext
region and after that they started
writing the vedas
so according to this
aryan invasion myth
the vedas were written somewhere around
1300 bce which is completely wrong i
mean that is a completely different
topic so there are a number of
misconceptions and all that we don't
know what the indus valley
civilization language was because we
have been unable thus far to decipher
the script
sanskrit is at least
3500 years old and the methane uh
evidence that we have of the sanskrit in
the mithani kingdom
is of post-vedic sanskrit
or or late vedic sanskrit it is not
rigged with sanskrit so it is clear that
the rigveda was written before that
so there are all these different pieces
of evidence that we need to put together
to try and answer
these very important questions as of
today we don't have evidence that can
conclusively demonstrate how old the
sanskrit language actually is
kushal gowda says why was the angkor wat
temple abandoned and why are no rituals
performed there
so this is the greatest and largest
hindu temple in the known universe the
angkor wat temple complex
cambodia right it's in it's in cambodia
so it has been found
the best evidence that we have
tells us that there was a massive uh
episode of climate change first you had
very extremely heavy rainfall for a very
long period of time
which forced the people to abandon this
this temple complex and then you had a
period of extended drought
and that's why
this place was completely abandoned
right so that's why this
temple complex was abandoned this great
nagara was abandoned
and that's why no rituals are performed
there and now cambodia has become a
buddhist country
the angkor wat temple was also later
repurposed into
a buddhist temple which is the same as a
hindu temple it's it's the same thing
like i've said buddhism and hinduism are
exactly the same thing there's no real
difference
so that in short is why this temple
complex was abandoned and that's why
it is now in ruins and no rituals are
performed there
okay next question why was there no
uprising or civil war against the
mughals
at least after aurangzeb's rule
so
was there no uprising or civil war
against the mughals or or war of
independence against the mughals
i mean who were the marathas
what were they doing
what did the great shatter pathway
he fought the mughals he fought
aurangzeb
the peshwas
after shivaji had see shivaji died young
he died too early he died prematurely if
he had been able to rule for another
another 20 30 years he alone possibly
could have reconquered all of india from
the mughals
but he died prematurely
and then the peshwas
created the maratha empire and they were
able to
reconquer
india from the mughals so there was
clearly an uprising against these
foreign barbaric occupiers of india
let's take a look at this
what does this map show us
this shows that the mughal empire was
annihilated
by the maratha empire the maratha empire
was able to establish hinduism
over india
it was able to conquer
much of india including parts of
afghanistan so there you have it
there was clearly an uprising against
the mughals a very
successful uprising
this okay
why was there no communist revolution in
india during the early 20th century
keeping in mind that the russian
revolution had occurred and even indians
were mostly workers in the british
factories both inside and outside india
it's because communism is completely
antithetical to indian culture it is
completely antithetical to dharmic
culture
communism is a dharma
right
see communism essentially is another
form of the abrahamic culture nothing
else
it also has one book
one prophet
and one religion
their book is the communist manifesto or
the das kapital
their prophet is karl marx
or engels or in some other flavors you
have mao
or lenin or stalin these are the various
prophets
and then you have one religion which is
the religion of marxism or socialism
whatever they call it it is completely
antithetical to indian culture
and that's why it never had any impact
in india
it is only now
now that india has become increasingly
destinated now that indians have lost
contact with their culture
india have law indians have lost their
roots it is now today in this new
environment that communism and marxism
and socialism are taking root in india
in people's minds because the education
system brainwashes
students into believing
these concepts as the right way of
approaching the world
so during uh the resistance against the
british india was very much still in in
touch
with its cultural ethos and that's why
marxism was not able to have any impact
in india
any significant impact in india
next question are yeti animals real
or not in the himalayas it's an
interesting question so there is this uh
supposedly mythical creature called the
yeti
that inhabits the himalayas in india in
tibet
and other parts of
in
other parts of the himalayan
mountain range it's called the yeti in
tibetan it's also called the migoi in
some places wild man or something like
that me means human i think
in this in the tibetan vermont languages
me means human
migoi i think it's called in some places
so
it is believed to inhabit the regions of
the himalayas in tibet in bhutan and
sikkim to
arunachal pradesh some regions also
do we have any evidence of this creature
not really
there have been certain photographs
taken by the indian army recently in in
the past by british explorers of these
very curious footprints very large
footprints in the snow in the himalayas
certain uh
bone fragments have also been found in
some
other
other evidence of this creature like
hair or or skin etc has been found but
it's not really been tested because it
disappeared etc
so is it possible that a large
hominid creature
could be could be living somewhere in
the himalayas
it is not impossible because this is a
very forbidding mountain range much of
it is unexplored only some peaks have
been climbed but much of this mountain
range is unexplored because it's so
inhospitable
so it is conceivably possible that some
isolated
population of such a hominid species
could exist somewhere there
we know that other species of humans
have lived until recently like the
homo florences for instance or the
denisovans neanderthals etc so maybe
there is some
archaic population isolated population
of such creatures still alive possibly
but the chances are very less the
probability is very less maybe it's a
myth maybe it's just a bear
or maybe it's an ancient memory of
an extinct
species
of hominid so we don't know for sure but
most likely it looks like it may not be
true
am i a spy because i can think i can
predict things accurately no i'm not a
spy i can i'm
if you study enough history if you study
enough geopolitics you're able to see
patterns you're able to see connections
that maybe other people cannot see and
that's why it's easier to
predict things accurately it has nothing
to do with spying i'm not
no spy
uh manish says
how can we restore our knowledge that
was lost during the destruction
of our ancient libraries like null in in
our universities like nanda sharda pete
etc
see
the texts that we lost in these great
destruct in these great fires will never
come back
we have lost the
records of thousands of years of our
history
much of it will
is lost forever unfortunately sadly
there are still millions of ancient
manuscripts that are gathering dust in
various temples and other places
that should be preserved that should be
restored that should be digitized it is
the job of the government of india to do
this it is not being done so actually
there is still much a great deal of
knowledge that still
is available to us
but it is still slowly crumbling away
into dust so that is one thing the
government of india needs to do it needs
to preserve these manuscripts it needs
to digitize this manuscript so that they
can be studied
whenever there is time so that scholars
have access to it you know
that needs to happen
what also needs to happen is we need to
start creating new knowledge
we need to reconnect with our
civilizational ethos which is
the worship of knowledge
indians
uh
regard knowledge in the
indians are very high regard for
knowledge
i mean
we know that very well
even a person who is illiterate
is is very respectful towards a person
who is very well read for instance so in
it is in our blood it's in our dna this
respect for knowledge
that we value knowledge so much so what
needs to happen is we need to reform our
education system and we need to start
producing
new knowledge
that's what needs to happen india needs
to become a world leader in the sciences
in philosophy in culture in the arts
again we can only do that if we reform
over the education system and we create
an education system that is geared
towards producing new ideas and geared
towards producing genuine leaders
that's what needs to happen
but the knowledge which was destroyed
in the destruction and burning of all
the universities and libraries that is
unfortunately gone we will not be able
to
restore that
aditya says how can we reverse the
tremendous brainwashing and the
destruction of self-respect and morale
done to us by the british
and partially by our own ancestors how
can we truly unite the country and its
citizens irrespective of caste creed
religion or language to ensure that
whatever happened to our country from
the invasion of gory etc to the
independence of 47
because of our divisions never happens
again
good question
uh
how do we reverse the brainwashing the
brainwashing
has a very clear mechanism
it is the indian education system the
colonial education system that
that
produces sheep instead of leaders
so you when a child is young before he
or she goes to school it's full of
curiosity it's full of this joy of life
it's full of curiosity it's full of
intelligence it's very inquisitive
it's very creative
the moment a child goes to school all of
that is smashed out of the child
and you're discouraged from asking
questions you're only
allowed to give answers
you are not allowed to think critically
you're not allowed to disagree you are
trained in obedience or absolute
unquestioning obedience and all of this
eventually leads to the brainwashing it
it conditions children's minds
in such a manner that when they reach
the right stage for example high school
that's when all these colonial ideas are
poured into their heads
through the social sciences social
studies education the humanities
education
and all the marxist socialist
brainwashing that is done in the higher
education system and all the fake
history that is taught to them so this
is the cause
of the brainwashing
and also because we are
forced to study in english so that also
puts every other language at an inferior
status
so it creates this sense of inferiority
it creates this slave-mindedness so the
first thing that needs to be done is to
adopt
our civilizational language as our
national language again sanskrit
secondly reform the education system get
rid of all these people who have been
brainwashing us and
reform the system
and thirdly we have to on our own
individually of our own initiative
try and look at the world in a different
way it's all about
reformulating how we think and how we
approach the world
for instance
we believe
that non-violence
and passivity
is the solution to every problem what
would mohandas gandhi do
if india is invaded
what should we do should we do
satyagraha at the border
what would gandhi do is the only
question that people ask
so why don't we ask ourselves
what would she do
what would
the goddess kali do
if there was an invasion of india if she
had to face an invasion would she turn
the other cheek would she go on a
satyagraha
no right so why does our culture why
does our
tradition
hold a goddess this they hold this form
of the mother goddess in such high
regard in high esteem
it's clear that we envisioned
situations and circumstances
in which this form of the mother goddess
should prevail over every other form or
the maternal
loving form of the mother goddess
right
so our ancestors understood
that non-violence and love is not the
answer to every situation
so why do we today
only look at the gandhian perspective of
everything
non-violence gandhi gandhi gandhi we
need to ditch this nonsense we need to
train ourselves
to be able to reformulate
questions and reframe questions
so that's what needs to happen and of
course the education system needs to
change so all of this will hopefully
contribute in
undoing and reversing the tremendous
brainwashing
and the destruction of self-respect and
morale that's been done over the past
thousand years the thousand years the
millennium of humiliation the chinese
have a century of humiliation india has
a millennium of humiliation we need to
start understanding this that we have
been
we have undergone this 1000 years of
humiliation only when we know this can
we do something about it
so we need to all educate ourselves and
the government needs to change things
change the education system
okay that brings me to an end of these
questions let me take some live
questions
some live questions
okay so if you have any live any any
questions that you would like to ask me
you can ask me now
okay what do we have
priyansh
says
i want to know about kalpa vigraha
the idol from
26460 bc
i am unfortunately not aware of what
this is
kalpavigra i'm not sure what to do i'll
try and look it up sorry
indian adivasi history indian history is
indian history we wish we need to stop
dividing ourselves into adivasis and one
of our seas and what not other vases
we're all indians our history is
see every part of indian history is
important it is all significant
but we are now trained into into seeing
these small categories within ourselves
so that in that that attitude needs to
be
we need to take
a new look at the this thing you know we
need to change our attitude india is um
enormous civilization and the history of
a certain segment adivasi's
i mean first of all do we even have
adivasis this this is a category that
has been created recently
in ancient indian literature over the
past 10 000 years this word adivasi
doesn't exist anywhere it only appeared
during the colonial times
so this is another example of people
trying to divide india you know that's
what it is
parikshit igbo says why do you hate ar
rahman so much
did i ever say i hate ar heman
i don't hate ar rahman i think he's a
mediocre musician
there is nothing special about him i
don't hate him why would i hate him
okay what else do we have some other
questions
you said india is ready for the next
chandragupta maurya
but shouldn't we first make the system
to allah allow able to allow genuine
leaders to take control and in power
there might be a lot of such people
today too listen if you there are two
kinds of changes one is a revolutionary
change and one is a reformative change
reforms take a great deal of time
revolutions are very destructive but
they can
bring about change very fast
if you want to first reform the system
gradually slowly it's gonna take another
30-50 years
is india in a position to wait wait the
next 20 30 50 years
to change its system so that now we can
have good leaders emerging no
a good leader a great leader will emerge
irrespective of whatever system is there
that's the
that's the defining characteristic of a
great leader he or she is able to
overcome all kinds of adversity so
adversity is necessary for the emergence
of a great leader
if you have a very easy system in which
great leaders can emerge then you will
have good leaders emerging all the time
but great leaders won't emerge great
leaders emerge only in times of
adversity
and i would say that the time is right
now
okay some other questions
kishore asks a good question what if the
government doesn't change the education
system then we will need to find ways of
educating ourselves or our children
maybe maybe people need to think more
seriously about homeschooling
or to
or other things you know
because right now the world is changing
this pandemic has
has changed the entire way we approach
education today all learning is done
online
but very soon what's going to happen is
that all jobs are going to be skills
driven skills based
skills will become more important than
paper degrees paper degrees will very
soon become worthless it's going to
happen within this decade
so all of this this commercial education
system
which essentially churns out paper
degrees in exchange for lacks of rupees
it's going to become obsolete
it will happen naturally
it's going to happen
so you know there are these forces of
nature so to say or forces of society
which force change
whether the government likes it or not
the government will want to keep this
system alive because they are most
comfortable with it the government and
the bureaucracy don't like change but
things will change anyway it's just a
matter of time
but will it change in the right
direction is the question
all right let me take one more question
look i don't know about the karkota
dynasty whether it was related to these
kittens or not
clearly there is there is a
similarities between the in the
territorial expanse of the sun god bring
the being the primary deity
it is possible
the karkota dynasty is clearly a
post-schitan invasion dynasty
so yeah there could be some sketching
elements
in the king kings or the
kings of the karkota dynasty it's quite
possible
i'm sure
everybody in northern and western india
has some skitian ancestry and we know
that the skits also have themselves had
indian ancestry this is a circular thing
it's not really important whether they
were related to the skittions or not
they were the karkota's were an indian
dynasty and that's what it is
so that's the answer in brief
okay yusinor says where do we find
evidence of buddha's death bed discourse
where he said he believes
in the soul and accepts the authority of
the vedas
any specific book to refer let me try
and pull it up online right now just
give me a minute
just a minute
let me google that up
let me share
this article with you
so this is an article by dr subhash
who has appeared on this
on this youtube channel
the article is called the buddha in the
veda it does contain references to what
you're asking
so what you what we need to do is we
need to find ways
of
of discovering information if you want
to know
about buddha's deathbed discourse the
first thing we should do is to google it
and it's all available online in the
public domain the actual translation of
the mahapari nirvana discourse is
available online
and i think this article itself has
links to that if i am not mistaken so
take a little bit of initiative
google it
and you will you will discover the truth
so the article's name is the article is
called the buddha in the veda the author
is dr subhash
i hope that answers your question let me
take one more question for today
let me see
something i have not answered something
that is relevant to
history
okay
lotha swaminathan says where brahman's
really evil
why is there so much anti brahmin hatred
in india
brahmal's brahmins were not powerful
people
they were the people who were in charge
of preserving and propagating
our ancient knowledge
the people in power
in political power were the chatrias
they were the aristocracy the nobility
of india
political power
always
flows from either the barrel of a gun or
from the
blade of a sword it doesn't come from
knowledge knowledge is not really power
it is
the
potential for unleashing violence
that gives birth to political power and
that always was in the hands of the
chatrias so how are brahman's evil
the reason there is so much anti-brahmin
hatred in india is because these people
the so-called liberals the marxists and
this entire
ecosystem
they want to stamp out hinduism from
india and hinduism all the knowledge all
the traditions were preserved and still
are to some extent
by the brahmanas
so they want to demonize the brahmanas
so that these traditions die out with
them
and it is all done by various political
parties and various academic
cliques and kabbals etc
and so on so that is
in brief why there is so much anti
brahmin sentiment and hatred in india
that's it
okay i think
i think i think that's it for today it's
been a very interesting session very
long nice session thank you so much
for all the questions thank you very
much i appreciate it
so i will see you very soon i will see
you next week next week is going to be
different
i will put out the schedule tomorrow or
day after most likely tomorrow morning
india time
so stay tuned for that thank you so much
thank you very much again
and i will see you very soon
have a good day have a good night
bye